

CONTACT



Dhahran, Saudi Arabia



+966545668444



Doha.fozan@gmail.com

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Human Resource
Management, 2019
Prince Mohammad Bin Fahd
University

CERTIFICATIONS

- Talent Acquisition freelancing.
- Office Management
- Secretarial Course.
- The Seventh Annual HRM Summit (Bahrain)

LANGUAGES

Arabic: Native language

English: Foreign Language

SKILLS

- Saudi Labor Law
- Payroll control
- Entrial & external recruitment
- Performance management
- Employee relations
- Training and development
- HR Policies & strategies
- Experience in ERP System.

Doha Al Fowzan

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Human Resources employee with years of experience managing hiring and onboarding, employee benefits and payroll, performance tracking methods, and HR records. Reliable, knowledgeable, and highly organized team player with excellent communication skills, team building, and relationship management.

WORK HISTORY

Employee Relations Lead Landmark Group - Khobar, Eastern Province

12/2022 - Current

- Handling employee complaints, managing grievance procedures and facilitating counseling in conjunction with other stakeholders.
- Ensuring the Company's treatment of employees is consistent with its core business values and objectives.
- Investigating and resolving complex or critical employee relations issues in a timely and effective manner.
- Collating and analyzing employee feedback across all levels on a regular basis and revising people programs and policies to generate more positive outcomes.
- Advised line managers on correct disciplinary procedures for compliant issue resolution.
- Managed performance appraisal systems and policies.
- Recruited, hired and trained new employees to optimize profitability.
- Provided strategic direction for human resources management team.
- Created succession plans and promotion paths for staff.
- Improved business HR policies by guiding and collaborating with managers.

Human Resources Supervisor

11/2020 - 11/2022

Samara Trading Group - Khobar, Eastern Province

- Prepared new hire letters, employee contracts, and corporate policies.
- Oversaw exit interviews and off-boarding process for resigned and terminated employees.
- Managed Interviews and Recruiting process.
- Preparing Monthly Payroll.
- The development and implementation of HR initiatives and systems.
- Arrangements internally, from accommodation travel to operational expenses.
- Update policies
- Prepared Organizational chart, Job offer form, job descriptions, employment contract, posting ads, and end of service settlement.
- Managing Evaluation and Objective processes.
- Issue new work permeance, transfer Iqama renewal, Update passport data, Re-entry
- Experience in Saudization, Ministry of Commerce, Mudded, Wage protection, Labor Office, Gosi, Hadaf, Tamm, Salama · Asharqia Chamber, Muqeem, and Qiwa.
- Experience in ERP System.
- Apply promotions and position changes.
- Coordinate training and handle logistics with administrative tasks.
- Assisted senior management with making key decisions by developing.
- Anticipating each department's annual and quarterly hiring needs.

07/2019 - 12/2020

Human Resources Specialist

Samara Trading Group - Khobar, Eastern Province

- Maximized productivity by coaching and developing performance management.
- Created succession plans and promotion paths for all staff.
- Prepare Organizational chart, offer form, job descriptions, employment contract,
- Preventing illegal working to ensure compliance.
- Provided strategic direction.
- Organizing Health Insurance for all the employees to ensure medical coverage as per Saudi labor of law.
- Controlling Staff Loans, Advances, Leave Management under ERP, Staff Annual, Ticket Record, Staff Travel
- payroll processing and benefits for over [400] employees.
- Tracked programs closely to assess the effectiveness and make proactive changes to meet changing demands.
- Developed and implemented recruiting strategies.
- Maximized HR efficiencies by, employment interviews, requisition posting and budgeting.

Human Resources Intern Raqtan company - Khobar, Eastern Province

02/2019 - 04/2019

- Recruitment Department: Job advertisement, contract sorting, interview, job offer, hiring and training and development and payroll Operations Department.
- Personnel Affairs Department: Employee files, database, vacations and registration in electronic services and experience in Saudization, Ministry of Commerce, Mudded, Wage protection, Labor Office, Gosi, Hadaf, Tamm, Salama Asharqia Chamber, Muqeem, and Qiwa.
- Administrative Affairs: Medical Insurance , flight tickets and housing transportation.